Carl Storms

Technology Evangelist | BIM Crusader | AECO Professional

With 25+ years of AECO experience, Carl excels in BIM and VDC, blending innovation with practicality. A curious learner of coding, automation, and Al-driven solutions, he's always eager to discuss the latest trends. Constantly exploring cutting-edge technologies and workflows, Carl shares his insights through blogging, podcasting, and speaking.

carl.storms@gmail.com

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

linkedin.com/in/cstorms

1-403-554-0564

bio.link/thebimsider

github.com/TheBIMsider

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

AECO Workflows & Digital Transformation AI & Machine Learning in AECO Mentorship **API Integration & Automation** BIM/VDC Strategy & Implementation Change Management & Process Optimization Community Engagement & Evangelism Low-Code & No-Code Development Data Analytics & Visualization Thought Leadership Storytelling & Content Creation

Project Information Management (PIM)

Public Speaking & Presentation

Tech Troubleshooting & Problem-Solving



WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Success Manager Newforma

01/2020 - Present

- Driving product adoption and customer success through advocacy and education.
- Equipped sales teams with industry knowledge, product demos, and strategic insights, to improve conversion rates and streamline the sales process.
- Conducted in-depth analysis of current and emerging industry platforms, creating training materials and content to inform sales strategies and product positioning.
- Oversee special projects within the organization for emerging technologies.

Solutions Consultant IMAGINIT Technologies

08/2012 - 01/2020

- Assess client's current business processes to recommend and implement solutions and application support for client BIM workflows
- Deliver application training to our clients, and industry-related technical presentations at seminars, workshops, conferences, user groups, both onsite and remotely. Customize training solutions where applicable
- Act as a brand ambassador seizing opportunities to increase IMAGINiT's visibility in the AEC marketplace

Instructor, School of Construction SAIT Polytechnic

05/2010 - 12/2012

- Instructor for Revit Architecture Fundamentals, Intermediate and Advanced Courses
- Assisted with deployment of new online Distance Learning Revit Architecture Intermediate and Advanced classes, including development of schedule and outlines
- Created new final exams for all three levels of the Revit Architectural courses

WORK EXPERIENCE

BIM Coordinator, IFP - Calgary International Airport

EllisDon Construction Services

05/2011 - 08/2012

- Led BIM/VDC coordination on projects, facilitating consultants, trades, and subcontractors through project phases.
- Managed 3D modeling processes for estimating, scheduling, logistics, and coordination, ensuring project-specific implementation.
- O Provided project deployment support, including software setup, training, and 4D scheduling collaboration.

Kasian Architecture Interior Design and Planning Ltd.

BIM Support Specialist

07/2010 - 05/2011

- Provided technical support and training to local model keepers, project teams, and individual users while developing and updating BIM training materials.
- Ensured consistent adherence to BIM standards and procedures, regularly auditing Revit and AutoCAD projects.
- Ocordinated BIM workflows with other disciplines and consultants to maintain seamless project integration.

Kasian Architecture Interior Design and Planning Ltd.

Architectural Technologist

08/2008 - 07/2010

- Created design, production, working, and presentation drawings.
- Assisted with building permit submissions and resolved building detail issues.
- Participated in design and production meetings.

Alberta Sales Coordinator

StairWorld Inc.

01/2007 - 08/2008

- Handled business development, cold calls, sales quotes, and presentations.
- Followed up on all sales and quotes in Alberta.
- Managed product deliveries and client orders across Alberta.

Design, Estimating, Marketing, CNC Operation

Redstone Custom Door Ltd

03/2005 - 01/2007

- Created design, shop, and installation drawings.
- Prepared presentation drawings for sales and marketing.
- Programmed and operated a 3-axis CNC for wood, veneer, and plastic parts production.

Architectural Technologist

Peake Design Group

08/2003 - 03/2005

- Oreated working and as-built drawings for custom homes, acreages, and major renovations.
- Worked with builders and trades to ensure accurate and timely project completion.
- O Developed 3D concept models using SketchUp.

Technical Engineering and Design

D&B Lumber & Supplies Ltd.

06/2001 - 08/2003

- Production of I-joist floor layouts in AutoCAD.
- Engineering of beams and joists for residential homes.
- Estimation of materials needed to build flooring systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Sales, Team Leader StairWorld Inc.

08/1998 - 11/2000

- Office Management Handled product purchasing and delivery schedules.
- International Sales Managed sales of products and complete curved stair systems.
- Stair Design & Documentation Created stair designs and shop drawings.

EDUCATION

Architectural Tech Diploma Algonquin College

1995 - 1998

2 Years of Law/Psychology Major Carleton University

1993 - 1995

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ACC/BIM 360 Al Prompts AutoCAD BIM Dynamo **HTML JavaScript** LLM Power BI VS Code MS Office Newforma Konket/BIM Track Navisworks Python Revit **VDC**

SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

165+ Presentations at Conferences, Trade Shows, User Groups, Webinars & More (2013 - Present)

AU, BCS, BILT, bSNC, CanBIM, DBWa, DCW, HxGN, RTC & More

 For over 10 years, I've had the privilege of speaking worldwide about BIM, VDC, AECO, and AI - from major conferences to local user groups, live or virtual. Along the way, I've been honored as a top speaker eight times. <u>Full list here</u>

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Cat Caregiver

Canadian Animal Task Force

01/2023 - Present

Industry Expert CCA, AECO Task Force on BIM

03/2015 - 08/2018

Fundraiser and Foster Host

Cats Home Foundation

08/2022 - Present

Industry Advisor for Capstone University of Calgary

09/2011 - 05/2012

HONOR AWARDS

Top Speaker (2024)

BILT Australia & New Zealand (ANZ)

TOP 3 Boardroom Roundtable Sessions (1st) (2019)

BILT North America (NA)

TOP 3 Large Presentations (3rd) (2019)

BILT North America (NA)

Top 10 Speaker (6th) (2018)

BILT Asia

Circle of Excellence (2017)

IMAGINIT Technologies

Top Speaker - Co-Speaker (2023)

Digital Built Week Americas (BILT NA) (Sean Fruin was Speaker)

TOP 3 Boardroom Roundtable Sessions (2nd) Co-Speaker (2019)

BILT North America (Marcello Sgambelluir was Speaker)

Top 10 Speaker (3rd) (2018)

BILT North America (NA)

Honorable Mention for Top 10 Speaker (11th) (2017)

BILT North America (NA)

© CERTIFICATES & TRAINING

Autodesk Expert Elite (2020 - Present)

Computer Programing Level 1 (ICT 710) (2019)

University of Calgary Continuing Education

Autodesk Certified Instructor - Silver (2019)

Revit Architecture Certified Professional (2017)

Revit Structure Certified Professional (2015)

Sandler Bronze Certification (2024)

Computer Programing Level 2 (ICT 711) (2019)

University of Calgary Continuing Education

Autodesk Certified Instructor (2017)

Revit MEP Certified Professional (2015)

AutoCAD Certified Professional (2014)

BLOGS & PODCASTS

Blog

The BIMsider

2014 - Present

Podcast Host

The BILT Academy Podcast

2020 - 2022

Podcast Co-Host

The Simply Complex Podcast

2016 - 2023

Podcast Host

Wrenches Gadgets & Hacks

2024 - Present

Podcast Co-Host

BIMThoughts

2020 - 2022

Podcast Co-Host

BluePrints

2016 - 2019

• INTERESTS

3D Printing

ΑI

Blogging

Coding

Low-Code

Music

No-Code

Podcasting

Sports

Technology